

Sakshi Raut Software Development Engineer

9172579828 sakshiraut736@gmail.com Nagpur, Maharashtra

SUMMARY

A full stack developer with one year of professional experience in the field. I have a strong background in front-end and back-end technologies including React, Angular, Java, Spring-Boot and various database languages like SQL, PostgreSQL as well as IoT and machine learning. I am dedicated to self-learning and is adaptable to collaborating with cross-functional teams.

EXPERIENCE

09/2022 - Present

Software Development Engineer

Brillio

- Worked on the Project where we developed a training platform using Java, Spring Boot for the backend environment and AngularJS for the frontend. The database was created and integrated using SQL workbench.
- Engaged with the leadership team of organisation for business research and growth
- Worked on Sun Pharma Project for development of Multiple websites using react and AEM architecture

01/2022 - 06/2022

Software Developer Intern

Wingrow Agritech

Designed and enhanced the user experience of website using React JS also collaborated with backend team

07/2021 - 12/2021

Machine Learning Intern

ML and speech-processing and analysis Intern.

Worked on speech processing and machine learning project to classify gender using ML models.

EDUCATION

2022 Electronics and Telecommunication

Vishwakarma Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Technology

 Project Oriented learning of subjects of VLSI (Very large system Integration), Embedded system, Digital Signal Processing(DSP), Computer Vision and IoT,

2018 **12th PCM Electronics**

Tarkunde Dharampeth Junior College, Nagpur Higher Secondary Education (State Board)

2016 **10th**

Christanand School and Junior college

Secondary School Education

CERTIFICATES

02/2023 - Present Angular JS complete guide

06/2022 - Present Modern Java 8

SKILLS

Java MySql AngularJS Python

SpringBoot Jupyter Notebook

HTML and CSS ReactJS
JavaScript Github
TypeScript OpenCV

NodeJS

LANGUAGES

English Fluent Marathi Native

Hindi Fluent